#### **Lado Oniani**

## ArtistSoftware and mechanical engineer



#### **Contact and information:**

• Email: <a href="mailto:ladooniani@gmail.com">ladooniani@gmail.com</a>

• Address: Tbilisi, 5 Sulkhan Tsintsadze St, 0160

Phone: +995 599 38 25 09Date of birth: 08-04-1980

• Link: https://github.com/ladooniani

## **Objective:**

My research and development in computational logic and mechanics focused on the invention and investigation of synthetic entity architecture, experimental and assistive educational, therapeutic, social, and humanitarian interactive and robotic technologies and concepts.

In 2016 I've founded an independent laboratory startup, inventing and prototyping program and mechanism of artificial entity robotic system, developing computing methods and techniques in computational linguistics, natural language processing, understanding and generation, machine learning, computer vision, mechanical engineering, and industrial/artistic design.

As a freelance software engineer, I provide desktop and web/mobile front/back-end full-stack development services of product complex solutions for different types of applications, as well as specialized tasks in intelligent robotics and related types of design.

My motivation in engineering is an interest that challenges me to find and create helpful solutions for real-world tasks with proficiency in computer programming, data structures, and algorithms, quickly learn and generate creative approaches, understand software design and find the best practices.

#### **Skills:**

- Software engineering and programming
- · Mechanical engineering
- Micro-controllers
- 3D design, part and assembly modeling
- · Artistic and industrial design

### **Programming languages and frameworks:**

- C# (.NET Framework WinForms, WPF, ASP.NET (Web Forms, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Web Pages) / .NET Core UWP, ASP.NET Core)
- TypeScript (Angular, Ionic)
- JavaScript (AngularJS MVC)
- Python (PyQT desktop application, Flask web framework)
- PHP, HTML, HTML5, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap
- DBMS: MySQL (SQL), PostgreSQL, MSSQL, Firebase
- C++ (Microcontrollers)
- Pascal

# Desktop and web application types development experience:

- Editors
- NLP semantic analysis algorithms
- Computational algorithms
- Chatbots
- Graphic algorithms

- Generators
- Machine learning applications
- Analytics and classification
- Computer Vision applications
- Robotics applications
- Game development
- CMS Website Blog
- · UX/UI design

#### Interests and fields of research:

- Computational semantics
- Computational linguistics
- Natural language processing-understanding/generation
- Algorithm design
- · Machine learning
- · Deep learning
- Computer vision
- · Cognitive science
- · Chat-bot development
- Mechanics
- Mechatronics
- Robotics
- Animatronics

## **Experience:**

• May 2005-August 2010

SOS Children's Villages Georgia National Association (Tbilisi, Georgia)

#### **Software Engineer**

Software development for educational tasks. Cases consideration with teachers

• July 2011-December 2014

Hi Life Interactive, LLC (275 Madison Avenue, 4th Fl, New York, NY 10016)

#### Engineer, composer, sound expert

Software engineer on sound processing tools, composer, sound expert

• October 2016-Present

TAI laboratory (Tbilis, Georgia)

#### Founder, researcher, software and mechanical engineer

The research and development in computational logic and mechanics, invention and investigation synthetic entity architecture, experimental and assistive educational, therapeutic, social, and humanitarian interactive and robotic technologies and concepts

#### **Education:**

• 1997-2001

**Technical University** 

Automated systems of control and data processing

Systems engineer

• 1998-2001

Academy of the Humanitarian Arts

Fine arts

Graphic artist and study of art

#### Languages:

- English
- Georgian
- Russian
- Spanish